channel5.com 2012-05-05

# Privacy Statement | Channel 5

Channel 5 is part of the Northern & Shell Broadcasting Limited group of companies, which is affiliated to the Northern & Shell Network Limited group of companies (together “the Northern & Shell Group”). This privacy notice explains how we use any personal information we collect about you when you use this website.

If you agree, we may pass on your personal information to other companies in the Northern & Shell Group so that they may offer you their products and services.  The Northern & Shell Group will not share your information for marketing purposes with other third party companies outside the Northern & Shell Group without your consent.

We would like to send you newsletters and information about our products and services and products and services of other companies in the Northern & Shell Group, or selected third party offers that may be of interest to you.  If you have consented to receive marketing, you may opt out at a later date.  You have the right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes or giving your information to other companies in the Northern & Shell Group.

Topics:

  * What information do we collect about you?
  * How will we use the information about you?
  * Users under 16
  * Chat rooms
  * Marketing and Third Parties
  * Access to your information
  * Cookies and IP addresses
  * Third Party Advertising Cookies
  * Other websites
  * Changes to our privacy notice
  * How to contact us, update your information or delete your account

 **What information do we collect about you?**  
We may collect information about you when you register on any of our sites, register for one of our fan clubs or promotions, request brochures or information, enter a competition, comment, vote or rate material on our sites, when we process orders from you for programmes you order from Demand 5, or when you provide us with information about yourself for any other purpose described to you on the site. Website usage information is also collected using cookies.

You are in control of the information you provide about yourself but if you choose not to share your information with us some of the areas of our websites may not be accessible to you.

 **How will we use the information about you?**  
We collect information about you to manage and operate your accounts with us, to contact you if we think you might be interested in contributing to Channel 5's programmes or to the website, to fulfil any competition prizes you have won, and if you agree, to email you and/or send you by SMS newsletters and information about other products and services, or selected third party offers that we think may be of interest to you. We use your information collected from the website to personalise your repeat visits to our website.

If you agree, we may pass on your personal information to our group of companies so that they may offer you their products and services.  Northern & Shell PLC will not share your information for marketing purposes with companies outside the network without your consent.

In processing your order for programmes from Demand 5 your details may be sent to, credit reference and/or fraud prevention agencies, which may keep a record of that information.

If you win a prize on Free Bingo, your details will be sent to 192.com for age verification purposes.  192.com will check the name and address details you provided when registering against several different sources, including the electoral roll and telephone directories.  The information you provided on registration may also be disclosed by 192.com to credit reference agencies, which may keep a record of that information. 

We store any information collected about you safely and will only retain your information for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.  Your information will then be securely deleted. 

**Children**  
Children under the age of 13 are not allowed to register with this website, and must not try to give any personal information to this website.  If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information.

If you are under the age of16, please obtain your parent/guardian's permission before you provide personal information to the website. 

**Chat Rooms**  
Our websites provide chat rooms and may make news groups available to users.  Users of these services are warned that such chat rooms and news groups are public discussion forums.  Any personal information supplied by users is widely accessible.  We do not monitor and are not responsible for the content posted on these services.  Use or exchange of profane or sexually explicit comments or material on the website chat rooms is prohibited.  The posting of any unlawful material is also prohibited.

 **Marketing and Third Parties**  
We would like to send you newsletters and information about our products and services and products and services of other companies in Northern & Shell, or selected third party offers that may be of interest to you.  If you have consented to receive marketing, you may opt out at a later date.  You have the right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes or giving your information to other members of Northern & Shell PLC.  If you have a channel5.com account and no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please[ log in to your account](http://www.five.tv/user/login), click on “Manage newsletter subscriptions”, where you can opt out of receiving marketing materials. 

We will also pass on your information to third parties where this is necessary to provide you with the goods or service you have requested or any competition prize due to you.   Your information will not be transferred outside of the European Economic Area without adequate protection.  We reserve the right to transfer any personal information to a third party in the event that we sell the whole or part of our business.

 **Access to your information**  
You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email us or write to us at address at the end of this notice.  We will charge £10 to cover our costs in providing this information to you. If possible, please pay the £10 fee by cheque (made payable to Channel 5 Broadcasting Limited) or BACS transfer (email us or write to us at the address below for our account details). We also accept payment by cash and postal order. We are not liable for any payment (however made) lost in the post or not received by Channel 5 for any other reason. 

**Cookies and IP addresses**  
Cookies are text files placed on your computer by your web browser or by Adobe Flash applications (also known as Local Shared Objects) to collect visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track your use of the website, to compile statistical reports on website activity and to allow the website to be customised.  We may also match information gathered from cookies to the information you choose to give about yourself when you register an account on the website. 

The use of cookies also enables us to recognise you when you return to the website. This saves you time because you will not have to fill in forms that you have already completed and it helps us to understand what interests you on the website which allows us to make the information we provide relevant to you.

You can set your browser not to accept cookies or Local Shared Objects and the websites below tell you how to remove these from your browser.  However, in a few cases some of our website features may not function as a result.

We may also log your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address to help diagnose problems with our servers, for system administration, for security and law-enforcement purposes. We do not link these addresses to any person’s name or other identifying information, unless required to do so by law.

For further information visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/), and for information on Local Shared Objects stored by Adobe Flash applications [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager06.html). 

**Third party advertising cookies**  
Most of the advertisements you see on our sites are generated by third parties. Some of these third parties generate their own cookies to track how many people have seen a particular advertisement (or use the services of other third parties to do this), and to track how many people have seen it more than once.  These cookies cannot be used to identify an individual; they can only be used for statistical purposes, for example, in providing you with advertisements that are more relevant to your interests.  Some of the information obtained from third party cookies will be aggregated with other anonymous information for statistical purposes.  The third party companies that generate these cookies have their own privacy policies and Channel 5 does not have access to these cookies; other than allowing them to be served and we have no role to play in these cookies (although we may use statistical information arising from these third party cookies and provided to us by third parties, to improve the targeting of advertisements to users of the website). 

If you would like to disable "third party" cookies generated by advertisers or providers of targeted advertising services, you can turn them off by going to the third party's website and getting them to generate a one-time "no thanks" cookie that will stop any further cookies being written to your machine.  Here are links to the main third party advertising platforms we use, each of which have instructions on how to do this:   
[http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/ad-cookie/ ](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/ad-cookie/)  
<http://www.audiencescience.com/privacy.asp>  
<http://creativezone.mediamind.com/Content.aspx?Page=PrivacyPolicy>  
<http://www.mediacontacts.co.uk/privacy-statement.php>  
<http://specificmedia.co.uk/privacy.php#optout>  
<http://www.tidaltv.com/PrivacyDashboard.aspx>  
<http://www.criteo.com/en/privacy-policy>  
<http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/uk/yahoo/details.html>

<http://inskinmedia.com/privacypolicy.html>

You can also visit the trade body representing these advertising bodies for more information on how to opt out of these cookies: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>.

Note: Following amendments to the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, we are currently working towards implementing the new requirements relating to the use of cookies.

 **Other websites**  
Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy notice only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy notices.

 **Changes to our privacy notice**  
We keep our privacy notice under regular review and we will place any updates on this webpage.  This privacy notice was last updated on 28th March **2012**.

 **How to contact us, update your information or delete your channel5.com and/or Demand 5 account**  
To update your information on your channel5.com account please [log into your account](http://www.five.tv/user/login). 

You can also contact us:

  * by email;
  * or write to us at: Data Protection Officer, Channel 5, 10 Lower Thames Street, London, EC3R 6EN.

If you would like to delete any of your accounts with us permanently, please send us an email instructing us to delete your account and specifying which account you would like us to delete, if applicable.  Once we receive your email, your account will be deleted as soon as is reasonably practicable.
